to
live. live
Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters
to another Wednesday question and answer
where we open up with the 10
Commandments that God commanded the
world to keep.
Brother Jerome,
or is it brother Julius?
I'll read it. Exodus
Yeah.
Exodus 20 20 1 through 17
And God speak all these words saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shalt have no
other gods before me.
Thou shalt not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of anything that
is in the heaven above, or that is in
the earth beneath, or that is in the
water under the earth. Thou shalt not
bow down thyself to them, nor serve
them. For I the Lord thy God am a
jealous God, visiting the iniquity of
the fathers upon the children unto the
third and fourth generation of them that
hate me.
And showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy.
Six days shalt thou labor and do all thy
work.
But the seventh day is the Sabbath of
the Lord thy God. In it thou shalt not
do any work, thou, nor thy son, nor thy
daughter, nor thy man servant, nor thy
maid servant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth,
the sea, and all that in them is, and
rested the seventh day. Wherefore the
Lord blessed the Sabbath day and
hallowed it.
Honor thy father and thy mother, that
thy days may be long upon the land which
the Lord thy God giveth thee. Thou shalt
not kill. Thou shalt not commit
adultery. Thou shalt not steal. Thou
shalt not bear false witness against thy
neighbor.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's
house. Thou shalt not covet thy
neighbor's wife, nor his man servant,
nor his maid servant, nor his ox, nor
his ass, nor anything that is thy
neighbor's. That's Exodus 20 1 through
17. May the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of his word. In Jesus' name we
pray. Amen. Amen. Amen.
So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time.
The questions we will not answer
are the vague and long scripture
questions, as well as questions of
debate. We are not here to debate. We
are here to spread the true gospel of
Jesus. So please be as direct as
possible with your questions so we can
be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also keep
in mind that this is a live stream, so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you please keep them to a
two scripture maximum. Now let me
introduce to you the family that's on
the panel this evening. We got brother
Julius.
Good evening, everybody.
Good evening. We got brother Dre. Good
evening.
We got brother Jerome.
Grace and peace.
We got sister Deborah.
Good evening.
And we have sister Casey with us, as
well as the guest caller, and I'm
brother Cornell. What is our first
question of the program?
Yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Um Mrs. Wait asks for you to explain
what milk and strong meat means in
Hebrews 5 verses 13 and 14.
All right. Hebrews 5 13 and 14. What is
milk and strong meat? Brother Jerome.
Well, in both cases it is it is talking
about the milk of the word, and the meat
is also talking about the word of God,
too. But let's go read the um the verse
that you gave for the question. Hebrews
[clears throat] chapter 5, and Julius,
can you read just verse 13? We'll come
to 14 a little later.
But everyone that uses milk is
unskillful in the word of in the word of
righteousness, for he is a babe. Mhm.
Talking about being unskillful in the
word, and he he's referred to
or she's referred to as a babe. So let's
go to Ephesians chapter 4 and read verse
14 and 15, and we're going to tie that
with the 1 Corinthians.
Get it? Go ahead and read.
Ephesians chapter 4
verse 14
and 15.
That we henceforth be no more children,
tossed to and fro, and carried about
with every wind of doctrine, by the
sleight of men,
and cunning craftiness, whereby they lie
in wait to deceive.
But speaking the truth in love, may grow
up into him in all things, which is the
head, even Christ.
Yeah, so that we be henceforth no more
as children tossed to and fro, you know,
cuz you're not that skillful in the
word, so
you can be tossed to and fro with every
wind of doctrine that came about, and he
don't want us to be that, cuz and we
babes in the word if we like that, and
that's why the Lord got to give us the
milk of the word so that we can grow
in understanding.
Go to uh 1 Corinthians the 3rd chapter
and read verse verse 1 through 3.
1 Corinthians 3
verses 1, 2, and 3.
And I, brethren, could not speak unto
you as unto spiritual, but as unto
carnal, even as unto babes in Christ.
I have fed you with milk and not with
meat. For hitherto you were not able to
bear it, neither yet now are you able.
For you are yet carnal. For whereas
there is among you envying and strife
and divisions, are you not carnal and
walk as men?
Mhm. So he said, I'm feeding you with
milk cuz you're not able to deal with
the meat, cuz he's showing you examples
if you're still dealing with strife and
envyings and divisions,
you're carnal in your heart and in your
mind.
So you need to grow with the
milk of the word, because obviously
you're not able to handle the meat yet.
The deeper things of the word of God. Uh
Can we go to 1 Peter chapter 2 verse and
2?
1 Peter
chapter 2
verses 1 and 2. Yeah. Wherefore laying
aside all malice and all guile and
hypocrisies and envyings and all and all
speak evil speakings, as newborn babes,
desire the sincere milk of the word,
that you may grow thereby. That's good,
cuz he want us to grow, and he giving
you the sincere milk of the word that
you may grow like babes, cuz
physically babes can't eat no meat
anyway. That's why we give them milk.
And then when you get you some teeth in
your mouth, you after you get a little
older, you're able to chew some meat.
That's a physical way of talking about,
hey,
in the word of God, get that milk first
so that you could be able to
partake in the meat.
The milk the the meat of the word of
God, okay? One more place. Now let's go
back to that
uh Hebrews
5 and read verse 14.
Hebrews 5
verse 14.
But strong meat belongeth to them that
are full age, even those who by reason
of use have their senses exercised to
discern both good and evil. Yeah, and
that's why the Lord want us to meditate
on his word. Meditate on his laws,
statutes, and ordinances day and night.
And as we grow in that word, we are able
to receive the meat of the word. We will
get a better understanding, okay? To
discern between good and evil from
Genesis
to Revelations, okay? Uh one more place
and that'll be it. Let's go to Joshua
chapter 1 verse 8.
Joshua
This book of the law shall not depart
out of thy mouth, but thou shalt
meditate therein day and night, that
thou mayest observe to do according to
all that is written therein.
For then thou shalt make thy way
prosperous, and then thou shalt have
good success.
Amen. That's all I got.
All right.
Thank you for that light there, brother.
As we continue to move on, hope that
answered their question. Next one.
Moving on. Skywriter asks, what is the
parable about the prodigal son?
Prodigal son.
What is the
meaning behind that, brother Julius?
A parable is an earthly story with a
spiritual meaning.
With a spiritual meaning.
The parable Let's go to Luke the 11th
chapter. This is what you're referring
to.
Luke chapter 11 and Jerome, I'm sorry,
Luke chapter 15.
In short,
the parable
uh
of the prodigal son,
prodigal means wasteful spending.
Wasteful, you know how people get a lot
of money and they just go crazy and they
just waste their inheritance or they get
an inheritance and they just waste it
and go through it. Well, this is about
a son. We're not going to read the whole
thing, you read the whole thing on your
own. Luke chapter 15 and pick it up at
verse 11. We're just going to read one
verse or maybe a couple of verses and
we're going to get to the end of it
because I want you to read it on your
own and then once you read it, you'll
have the understanding of it. Luke 15
and 11.
Go ahead and read. And he said, "A
certain man had two sons.
And the younger of them said to his
father, 'Father, give me the portion of
goods that
falleth to me.'
And he divided unto them his living." Go
And what did he do with with his
inheritance? Go ahead.
And not many days after the younger son
gathered all together and took his
journey into a far country and there
wasted his substance with what righteous
living." So, he got his inheritance and
ran through it. Didn't save, didn't plan
for the future, just ran through it. So,
then what happened when he found out
that nobody would help him? Maybe one or
two people help him, but we He had to
depend on other people. Skip down to
verse 17 quickly.
And when he came to himself, he said,
"How many hired servants of my father's
have bread enough and to spare, and I
perish with hunger?
Go ahead. I will arise and go to my
father
and will say unto him, 'Father, I have
sinned against heaven and before thee
and am no Really, this is really a
parable about the nation of Israel and
how we how how the Lord put us on top
and we didn't appreciate it and we went
out into the world, got into paganism
and then
uh repented and came back. So, now let's
get to the end of this. Uh verse 32
because his older brother was upset that
when his when he came back home, his
father greeted him just like the Lord
rejoiced. The angels in heaven rejoice
when we turn back to God and start
serving him in truth and uprightness.
Verse 32. Look how the Lord feel and
this is how this father felt. Go ahead.
It was meet that we should make merry
and be glad for this thy brother was
dead and is alive again and was lost and
is found." And that is what this parable
is all about. It is about a son that was
lost, repented, recognized that he had
sinned against We sinned against our own
God, repent and come back to the Lord.
And that's what the parable of the
prodigal son uh is all about. Repent and
turning back to the Lord. Come out of
paganism, turn and serve the true and
living God. And the book said when we
turn to our God,
the angels in heaven rejoice when we
come out and we stop sinning and walk
right, the angels in heaven rejoice. So,
it's about coming back to the Lord.
That's what this parable is all about.
But read the whole read the whole uh
story on your own.
All right, thank you for that. There's
truly power in repentance.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
We're going to move on to our next
question.
Moving on, Be Alert asks, "In Leviticus
10 verse 1, is strange fire celebrating
other religious holidays that are not
given in Leviticus 23?
What is considered to be strange fire in
the sight of God?"
I don't know.
Okay. All right. So, we're going to go
to that Leviticus 10 and verse 1 and the
guest caller will take it from there.
It's about the strange fire.
Read it.
8 and 1.
And Nadab and Abihu, the sons of Aaron,
took either of them his censer and put
fire therein and put incense therein on
and offered strange fire before the
Lord, which he commanded them not.
Now, it says here that this strange fire
fire uh uh celebrate other religious
holidays
in Leviticus 23rd chapter.
The fire that uh uh
uh
In other words, deal with strange
doctrine. The whole thing is we don't
know.
Ain't nothing in the Bible that uh that
uh
that defines what this strange fire
represent. So, for me to give an answer,
that would be my opinion or
interpretation and I don't have an
opinion and interpretation.
The strange fire,
we don't know. Ain't nothing written on
it.
So, I'm going to have to say.
All right, hope that answered your
question. We're moving right on along.
Moving along, Be Alert also asks for
some understanding from 1 Corinthians 15
verse 23 and Jeremiah 2 verse 3.
All right. 1 Corinthians.
Well,
yeah, it just says Corinthians 15 and
23.
And we know it's no 2 Corinthians 15, so
it must be 1 Brother Dre, but can you
shed some light, please? Yeah, let's go
to 1 Corinthians 15
and Brother Jerome, can you start it at
verse 20 and read down to 23.
But now is Christ risen from the dead
and become the firstfruit of them that
slept.
For since by man came death, by man came
also the resurrection of the dead. For
as in Adam all die, even so in Christ
shall all be made alive. But every man
in his own order, Christ the
firstfruits, afterwards they that are
Christ's at his coming.
So, it's letting us know that Christ is
the first born from the dead. And he is
afterwards they that are Christ's. It
says, "In Adam all die
and Christ shall all be made alive." And
that verse 23 says, "But every man in
his own order, Christ is the firstfruit
and afterwards they that are Christ's at
his coming." Let's go to uh
uh Romans 8 and we're going to read
verse 29 and then we'll get to that
Jeremiah.
Go ahead, brother, when you get there.
Romans 8 verse 29.
>> [snorts]
>> Romans 8 and 29.
And it reads, "For whom he did foreknow,
he also did predestinate to be conformed
to the image of his son, that he might
be the firstborn among many brethren."
So, Christ is the firstborn among many
more to come. He is the firstfruit among
many more to come. Now, let's go to that
Jeremiah 2.
Jeremiah 2
and we're going to read verses 2 and 3
there.
Jeremiah 2
verses 2 and 3. Go ahead, brother.
Go and cry in the ears of Jerusalem,
saying, "Thus saith the Lord, I remember
thee the kindness of thy youth,
the love of thine espousal,
when thou wentest after me in the
wilderness, in a land that was not sown.
Israel was holiness unto the Lord and
the firstfruits of his increase. All
that devoured him shall offend. Evil
shall come upon them.
Evil shall come upon them, saith the
Lord."
So, Israel was holiness unto the Lord
and the firstfruit of his increase.
Let's go over now and look at Exodus 4
and read verse 22. Exodus 4 and 22. When
you get there, go ahead, brother.
Exodus 4 and 22. Yes, sir.
>> And thou shalt say unto Pharaoh, 'Thus
saith the Lord, Israel is my son, even
my firstborn.'"
>> So, Israel is his firstborn, but here,
let's look at one other place. Let's go
to Isaiah 49 and we're going to read
verse 6 and that'll be it. Isaiah 49 and
verse 6.
When you get there, go ahead, brother.
And he said, "It is a light thing that
thou shouldest be my servant to raise up
the tribes of Jacob and to restore the
preserved of Israel. I will also give
thee for a light to the Gentiles, that
thou mayest be my salvation unto the end
of the earth."
That's right. So, the Lord is is a light
thing to raise up Israel, but the Lord
is also going to be a light to the
Gentiles that he will be the salvation
to the ends of the earth. So, one here,
Jeremiah is talking about Israel and
Israel being the firstborn and uh 1
Corinthians 15 is letting you know about
Jesus being the firstborn from the dead.
That's all I got. All right.
All All
Thank you for that, brother.
Whosoever will, let them come, right?
Yes, sir.
All right.
We're going to move on to our next
question.
Next one, Toya Mullins says, "In the
Bible, there are some scriptures that
speak of the wife of a man's youth, but
some just say wife. Is there a
difference between the two? And what is
the definition of the wife of his
youth?"
All right, brother Julius, what is the
difference between those two?
The difference
The wife of of your youth is
the wife the the the wife that you
married while you was young.
She was a young woman chosen while
young, she gets married, and she
switches a covenant between husband and
wife.
And you grow old
together. That's why the preacher says,
"Till death do you part." Now,
uh let's let's give you an example of
the wife of your youth.
Let's go to Proverbs the fifth chapter.
Proverbs the fifth chapter. It just
means a young girl that got married
young.
Pick it up we going 18 uh to 20.
Let's look at how it's supposed Our God
set it up to be.
Go ahead at verse 18.
Let thy fountain be blessed and rejoice
with the wife of thy youth. Let her be
as the loving
hind and [clears throat]
hind and pleasant roe. Yes. Let her
breasts satisfy thee at all times and be
thou
>> uh only for two or three years.
Mhm. All times.
All times.
>> And and what?
At all times.
>> All times. Go ahead. And be thou
ravished always with her love. Always.
That's a long time. Keep going.
And why will thou, my son, be ravished
with a strange woman and embrace the
bosom of a stranger? And what And when
you do that, you're dealing
treacherously.
You're dealing treacherously. Let's go
to Malachi 2.
Malachi 2 and we going Jerome, we going
to read verses 14 to 16. Malachi 2 uh
pick it up at verse 13. Go ahead.
And this have you done again, covering
the altar of the Lord with tears, with
weeping, and with crying out, insomuch
that he regard not the offering anymore
or receive it with good with at
with goodwill at at your hand. Continue.
Yet ye say, "Wherefore?"
Because the Lord have been witness
between thee and the wife of thy youth.
And against
And against whom thou has dealt
treacherously. Yet it is she yet is she
thy companion and the wife of thy
covenant. Oh, my goodness. Go ahead. One
more.
>> not And did not he make one?
Yet he
the residue of the spirit and wherefore
one? That he might seek a godly seed.
Therefore, take heed to your spirit and
let none deal treacherously against the
wife of his youth. But if you choose if
you choose
Now, that's the wife of your youth, the
girl who you married when you when y'all
was young. Back to Proverbs the 18th
chapter. I got one spot after this.
Here's the difference.
Proverbs
18 and verse 22.
When you get it, go ahead.
Whoso findeth a wife findeth a good
thing and obtaineth favor of the Lord.
Did it say anything about the wife of
your youth?
That means whenever you get married
you don't have to be young to get
married. You You got people that get
married in their senior when they're
seniors uh in their late ages. One more
place after this. The book say, "Whoso
findeth a wife findeth a good thing and
obtaineth favor of the Lord."
Now, look what Paul told you in 1
Corinthians the seventh chapter.
This is last.
The wife of your youth is when y'all get
married young.
And then
he that findeth wife it don't have to it
don't set an age.
And this is why. 1 Corinthians 7, we
going to read verses 2 and then we going
to we'll skip to 8 and 9.
1 Corinthians 7 and 2. When you get it,
go ahead, my brother.
Nevertheless, to avoid fornication, let
every man
have his own wife and let every woman
have her own husband. Didn't give no
age, did it? Nope.
Didn't give no age. Skip down to verse 8
and 9.
8 and 9. I say therefore to the
unmarried and widows
it is good for them if they abide even
as I. Paul told us not to get married.
Go ahead.
But if they cannot contain, let them
marry. For it is better to marry than to
burn. So, the difference is the wife of
your youth is the the young girl when
y'all got married real young and y'all
grew old together. And then
uh a wife is whenever you get married.
That's your wife. It doesn't set an age
there. So, the difference is one is
young and one can be at at any age.
That's all I got, Cordell. I hope that
helped.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered their question as we
move on to our next one.
Moving on, JJ wants to know, "What's the
difference between hell and the lake of
fire? In Revelations 20 verse 14, it
points out that death and hell will be
cast into the lake of fire. And Isaiah 5
verse 14 says, 'The hell enlarges
herself.'"
All right. Well,
hell and the lake Hell is a state of
condition and the lake of fire is a
place of punishment.
So, let's go into Revelations 20.
Revelations 20.
And let's pick it up
brother, let's read that verse 10 and
then we're going to skip down.
Verse 10. Go right ahead.
And the devil that deceived them was
cast into the lake of fire and
brimstone, where the beast and the false
prophet are and shall be tormented day
and night forever and ever. All right.
So, this is saying being cast where the
beast and the false prophet have already
been in for a thousand years and they
shall be tormented day and night forever
and ever. So, this is a place that
they're going to be. It's like a fiery
prison, so to speak, cuz you get no
parole at that place. Skip down to read
14.
And And death and hell were cast into
the lake of fire. This is the second
death. And whosoever was not found
written in the book of life was cast
into the lake of fire. All right. So,
death, we talking about here, there'll
be no more death when it's cast into the
lake of fire. And hell shall be cast
into the lake of fire. But it's going to
be hell for those that's in that lake of
fire.
Let's go right into Revelations 21 and
see some hell we going through now,
which will show [clears throat] you it's
a state of condition, but the Lord is
going to do away with that. Revelation
21 and pick it up at that verse four.
Because there'll be no more this either,
these hellacious conditions, so to
speak. Go ahead, brother.
And God shall wipe away all tears from
their eyes.
And there shall be no more death,
neither sorrow nor crying, neither shall
there be any more pain. For the former
things are passed away. So, these are
all states of condition, death, which
was not meant to be, and pain and
sorrow. Lord is going to get rid of that
because that is considered also as
hellish conditions. Now, let's go
straight into Isaiah 5. They asked about
that one, too. Isaiah 5.
And when you get there, brother, let's
pick it up at that verse 13 and 14.
Isaiah 5 13 and 14. Show you another
condition of hell here, which can be
your problems, your situations, not
being able to pay your rent,
being homeless, not having nothing to
eat. Read, brother, 13 and 14. Then one
more after that and we'll be done. Go
ahead.
Therefore, my people are gone into
captivity because they have no
knowledge. And their honorable men are
famished and their to to dried up with
thirst. Therefore, hell have enlarged
herself and opened her mouth without
measure.
And their glory and their multitude and
their pomp and he that rejoiceth shall
descend into it. So, these are also hell
conditions here. When you have people
that are gone into captivity and don't
have no knowledge and they honorable men
are famished and hell shall enlarge
itself. When you look in our
communities, you see that we have a
hellish condition going on all around
the globe. Now, go to Isaiah 66 and read
that one verse 24 to show that this is a
lo- This is a place of punishment here.
Where we heard Satan will be thrown in
in that Revelations. Isaiah 66 and 24.
Read that, brother.
And they shall go forth and look upon
the carcasses of the men that have
transgressed against me. For their worm
shall not die, neither shall their fire
be quenched. And they shall be an
abhorring unto all flesh. So, this is a
location of punishment for all of those
that don't make the cut.
So, this is a location, but also within
that lake of fire, it is hell when worms
are eating on you and fire is burning
you up. That's all hell, too, but one is
state of condition, and another one is a
location of actual punishment where the
Lord is going to put all those that
don't make the cut. That's all I got.
All right, we hope that answered your
question as we keep on moving. What is
time check?
Yes, the time is 8:00. Lion of Judah
asks, "Will the great white throne
be here on Earth, not in heaven, when
the second resurrection happens?"
All right, so we're going to open this
one up to the panel, but we know the
whole show is going on here on Earth.
Not in heaven. Open to the panel.
Will the great white throne be here on
Earth, not in heaven, when the second
resurrection happens?
Let me look at it.
First thing is, let's see
Let's see where the Lord is going to
come. Let's go to Revelation 20th
chapter.
Mhm. Read 1 through 4.
And I saw an angel come down from
heaven, having the key of the bottomless
pit and a great chain in his hand. And
he laid hold on the dragon, that old
serpent which is the devil and Satan,
and bound him 1,000 years. And cast him
into a bottomless pit, and shut him up,
and set a seal on him that he should
deceive the nations no more till the
1,000 years should be fulfilled. And
after that, he must be loosed a little
season. And I saw thrones, and they sat
upon them, and judgment was given unto
them. And I saw the souls of them that
were beheaded for the witness of Jesus
and for the word of God, and which had
not worshipped the beast, neither his
image, neither have received his mark
upon their foreheads or in their hands.
And they lived and reigned with Christ
1,000 years.
Yep.
Now,
what verse was that? That was verse 4.
Down to verse 7 to continue. Let's look
at what's going to happen after 1,000
years. Go ahead.
And when the 1,000 years
are expired, Satan shall be loosed out
of his prison. And shall go out and
deceive the nations which are in the
four quarters of the Earth, Gog and
Magog, to gather them together to
battle. The number whom is as the sands
of the sea.
And they went up and they went up on the
breadth of the Earth and compassed the
camp of the saints about. And the
beloved city, and fire came down from
God out of heaven and devoured them.
Now, they say went up on the breadth of
the Earth.
So, this whole thing is being played
out, even you reigning with Jesus for
1,000 years.
But now, after the 1,000 year was over,
we skip down to verse 15 and let's see
what happened.
And whosoever was not found written in
the book of life was cast into the lake
of fire.
So, now, what happened is
Satan was cast into the lake of fire
first. Did you read verse 13?
No.
Verse 13.
>> verse
Okay.
And the sea And the sea gave up the dead
which were in it, and death and hell
delivered up the dead which were in
them. And they were judged every man
according to their works.
Uh-huh.
And death and hell
>> hell
But but but uh but before that, Satan
was cast into the lake of fire. So, I
don't have a book with me, so I'm saying
where what verse is it Satan Satan was
cast into the lake of fire?
Verse That's in that uh 10.
Verse 10?
Yep.
>> Yeah. Read Read from 10 to 13, okay?
Okay.
And the devil that deceived them was
cast into the lake of fire and
brimstone, where the beast and the false
prophet are, and shall be tormented day
and night forever and ever.
And I saw a great white throne and him
that sat on it,
from whose face the Earth and the
heavens fled away. And there was found
no place for them.
And I saw the dead, small and great,
stand before God, and the books were
opened. And another book was opened,
which is the book of life. And the dead
were judged out of those things which
were written in the books according to
their works.
And the sea gave up the dead which were
in it,
and death and hell delivered up the dead
which were in them. And they were judged
every man according to their works.
Now, now,
if you weren't in the book, where did
you go? Verse 15, read it.
And whosoever was not found written in
the book of life was cast in the lake of
fire.
Now, that's the white throne judgment.
But remember,
Jesus had to come to do this. So, now,
we going to see where this
we going to put see this lake of fire.
Let's go to Revelation the 19th chapter.
Back up
and read verses 11 verse 11 first.
19:11, read it.
And I saw heaven opened, and behold a
white horse. And he that sat upon him
was called faithful and true. And in
righteousness, he doeth judge and make
war.
Okay, this is the coming of Jesus. Now,
let's see what's going to happen when he
come. Who going to come with him? Read
verse 14.
And the armies which were in heaven
followed him upon white horses, clothed
in fine linen, white and clean.
And this army is his angels. We're not
going to mention about the saint, just
deal with the angels right now.
So, they coming with him. And what's
going to happen? Skip down and read
verse 19 and 20.
And I saw the beast, and the kings of
the Earth and their armies gathered
together to make war against him that
sat on the horse and against his army.
Go ahead.
I got my page a little tore up right
there.
>> [laughter]
>> And it was And the beast was taken, and
with him the false prophet that wrought
miracles before him, with which he
deceived them that had received the mark
of the beast and them that worshipped
his image. These both was cast alive
into a lake of fire burning with
brimstone.
Okay, now. So, we going to see where
this where this lake of fire was
located. Let's go to Isaiah 66. Read
verses 23 and 24.
And it came to pass that from one new
moon to another, and from one Sabbath to
another, shall all flesh come to worship
before me, said the Lord. And they shall
go forth and look upon the carcasses of
the men that have transgressed against
me. For their worm shall not die,
neither shall their fire be quenched.
And they shall be an abhorring to all
flesh.
So, that means that the lake of fire is
going to be on this Earth.
And everybody that goes in it going to
be on this Earth.
And the judgment is going to take place
on this Earth by Jesus, because Jesus
was sent to do one thing.
And this is the last place.
Isaiah 47.
Read verses 1 through 4.
Come
down and sit in the dust, O virgin
daughter of
>> I'm sorry.
>> 47.
Huh? This is Isaiah 42. I'm sorry. Okay.
Isaiah 42, 1 through 4.
Behold my servant whom I uphold,
mine elect in whom my soul delighteth. I
have put my spirit upon him. He shall
bring forth judgment to the Gentiles. He
shall not cry, nor lift up, nor cause
his voice to be heard in the street. A
bruised reed shall he not break, and a
smoking flax shall he not quench. He
shall bring forth judgment unto truth.
He shall not fail, nor be discouraged,
till he have set judgment in the Earth.
And the aisles shall wait for his law.
So, that's Jesus.
And everything after Jesus leave heaven,
everything then happens upon this Earth.
And nobody else gets to goes anyplace
else. So, the white throne judgment is
going to take place on this Earth. The
Father is not going to do the judgment.
Jesus is going to do the judgment.
And once the judgment is over with, then
Jesus going to turn over to the Father,
turn the Earth over to the Father, and
that's when you go to 21st chapter of
Revelation, and here come the Father
with New Jerusalem.
First Corinthians 15 will tell you then
Jesus delivered the kingdom unto the
Father.
So, it's going to be on this Earth.
That's all I have to say.
Yes, sir. Amen.
Thank you for that. Hope that answered
their question as we move on to our next
one.
Moving on, Kenya Haynes wants you to
explain Titus 3:5.
What is meant by regeneration
and renewing of the Holy Ghost?
All right, that Titus 3
and 5. What is meant by regeneration and
renewing of the Holy Ghost? Brother Dre,
what you say?
Let's go read that Titus 3. Pick it up
at verse 3 and read into 5. Brother
Jerome, when you get it, go ahead.
We ourselves also were sometimes foolish
and disobedient, deceived, serving
divers lust and pleasures, living in
malice and in envy, hateful, and hating
one another. But after that the kindness
and love of God
uh our savior toward man appeared,
not by works of righteousness which we
have done, but according to his mercy he
saved us by the washing of regeneration
and renewing of the Holy Ghost. So, it
wasn't our works because at some point
in our life we were sometimes foolish,
disobedient,
and serving all kind of lust. So,
it was his kindness and love that he
appeared and it wasn't by our works that
we have done, but according to his mercy
he delivered us by the washing of
regeneration
and renewing of the Holy Spirit.
Regeneration is is the cleaning and uh
fixing
of our minds from a degenerate mindset
to a a mind that has been regenerated
to serve him by the Holy Spirit. But,
let's go to uh John the 15th chapter.
John 15 and pick it up at verse 1.
John 15 and 1. Go ahead, brother, when
you get it.
I am the true vine, and my father is the
husbandman.
Go ahead.
Every branch in me that beareth not
fruit he taketh away. And every branch
that beareth fruit, he purge it, that it
may bring forth more fruit. So, he he he
is
every branch in him, he's going to purge
out the unfruitful parts.
And every branch in him that he purges,
they bring forth more fruit. But, go
ahead.
Now, you are clean through the word
which I have spoken unto you. Mhm. Abide
in me, and I in you. As a branch cannot
bear fruit of its itself, except it
abide in the vine, no more can ye,
except ye abide in me. So, now he said,
"Now, if you you are clean through the
word which I have spoken unto you." That
is the regeneration of your mind. That
is the Holy Spirit that has come down in
the form of the word that regenerates
your mind to serve him. Go ahead.
I am the vine, ye are the branches. He
that abideth in me, and I in him, the
same bringeth forth much fruit. For
without me, you can do nothing. That's
right. It is by him that we do these
things. Verse 8.
Verse 8. Go ahead, brother. Herein is my
father glorified, that ye may bear much
fruit. So shall ye be my disciples.
That's right. So, it is by him that we
are going to bear this fruit. And and in
that way we will be his disciples. I
meant verse 7. Verse 7. Go ahead. If ye
abide in me, and my words abide in you,
ye shall ask what ye will, and it shall
be done unto you.
Mhm. So, this is what is supposed to
abide in us, his word. That is what
abides in us. That is what regenerates
us. That is the spirit. Now, let's go
read one other place. John 6 and 63.
John 6 and 63.
Read that when you get there, brother.
It is the spirit that quickeneth, the
flesh profiteth nothing. The words that
I speak unto you, they are spirit, and
they are life. That's right. So, these
words is what is spirit and what is
life. And if we abide in those words, he
will abide in us. And that is what we're
regenerated by, by the Holy Spirit.
So, verse
I I want to read that verse 68. Read it,
brother.
Verse 67, verse 67 and 68. Go ahead.
Then said Jesus unto the 12, "Will ye
also go away?" Then Simon Peter answered
him, "Lord, to whom shall we go? Thou
hast the words of eternal life." Because
the words bring eternal life if we abide
in them.
Mhm. [clears throat] That's what we're
regenerated by, the Holy Spirit, that
word.
Yes, sir.
Yep. That's it, brother. You got to
constantly wash yourself with the word.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
As we move on to our next question.
Next one. Detroit Price asked, "In 1
Samuel 25 verse 39, when Nabal died and
David blessed the Lord for taking away
his reproach, is that the same as
rejoicing at the fall of your enemies as
stated in Proverbs 24 verses 17 and 18?"
All right. 1 Samuel 25
and verse 39.
And the guest caller will take it from
there.
Okay, read it.
And when David heard the that Nabal was
dead, he said, "Blessed be the Lord that
have
pleaded the cause of my reproach from
the hand of Nabal, and have kept his
servant from evil. For the Lord have
returned the wickedness of Nabal upon
his own head." And David sent and
communed with Abigail to take her to be
him to him to wife.
Now, you know, and I now read uh
Proverbs 24 and 17.
And
Proverbs 24:17 and 18.
Okay.
Proverbs 24 17 and 18.
Rejoice not when thine enemies falleth,
and let not thine heart be glad when he
stumbleth,
lest the Lord see it, and it displease
him, and he turn away his wrath from
him.
Now, first thing is, Nabal was dead.
So, how is the Lord going to turn away
his wrath from Nabal?
And David was not the uh uh uh
and David was not the uh rejoicing
uh uh
because uh at all.
He was praising God because if he not,
David was said he was going to go and
kill everything in Nabal's house.
Everything that urinated against the
wall.
Now, let's go back to 1 Samuel 20 25th
chapter. We're going to read verse 21
and 22
first.
1 Samuel 25:21.
And 22.
Okay.
Now, David had said, "Surely in vain
have I kept all that this fellow hath in
the wilderness, so that nothing was
missed of all that pertained unto him,
and he have requited me evil for good."
So, and more also do God unto the
enemies of David, if I leave all that
pertained to him by the morning light
any that piss against the wall.
Now,
David, you know, people say, "Well, you
know, he didn't ask David to do it."
But, still David kept everything he had.
And now, he could have showed some
appreciation. So, David got so mad, he
was going to go kill everybody.
But, then the Lord stopped him. Skip
down and read verse uh
uh uh
32 and 33.
And David said to Abigail, "Blessed be
the Lord God of Israel, which sent thee
this day to to meet me.
And blessed be thy advice, and blessed
be thou, which hast kept me this day
from coming to shed blood, and from
avenging myself with my own hand."
See, and that's what he was doing. He
was blessing God like he blessed Abigail
for stopping him from going and killing
a lot of people.
Yep.
He wasn't rejoicing over uh uh Nabal. He
said, "Hey, the Lord is the one that
took Nabal down." David didn't.
But, Abigail stopped it.
And he
and and when the Lord killed even uh
Nabal, David blessed the Lord.
And he didn't rejoice because he was
dead. He blessed the Lord mostly because
uh
the Lord stopped him from going and
killing a lot a lot of would have been
innocent people cuz he said,
"If by morning light any be left that
urinate against the wall. That mean he
was going to kill everybody to save it
even the woman cuz he said the Lord that
kept my hand back from killing you.
So he was blessing the Lord for stopping
what he was about to do which would have
been wrong.
He was not rejoicing over Nabal's fall.
That's all I have to got to say.
And that verse 38 guest caller, that
verse 38 tell you that the Lord smote
Nabal and he died.
That is right.
And and and David was not
He was not rejoicing.
That's all I have to say.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on with the time
check to the next one.
Uh the time is 8:20
and Stephen Googis asked, "What is
rounding the corner of your head and
beard
in Leviticus 19:27?
Also, is it a sin to do it even though
it's not written in the law which he
gives Exodus 20:1-17?"
All right. What is round the corner of
your head and beard Leviticus 19 and 27
and the guest caller take it from there.
Well,
I don't know what rounding the corner of
your head is
or your beard, but I know
that it is not sin.
Let me show you why.
Let's go into Genesis the 41st chapter
and read verse 14.
41st chapter verse 10?
Uh uh
41 and verse 14 cuz he said rounding the
head
and you know and cutting off uh
rounding the beard.
So
41 and 14.
Then Pharaoh sent and called Joseph and
they brought him hastily out of the
dungeon. And he shaved himself and
changed his raiment and came in under
Pharaoh.
So now Joseph shaved his whole beard
off. You understand what I'm saying?
Mhm. So if that was sin, he just
committed sin, but no, sin is the
transgression of the law.
Not cutting your hair or shaving your
hair or shaving off your beard.
That's all I have to say.
All right. I don't know how they tied it
all. So what's the second part of that
Deborah? Also, is it sin to do it even
though it's not written in the law?
It right which he gives the commandments
Exodus 20:1-17.
Oh, if it's not written in the law then
All right.
We have nothing further than that.
Do you [clears throat] transgress the
law?
And there's nothing in the 10
commandments that said thou shall not
uh uh shave your
round your head or
shave off your beard. Nothing.
Right.
Okay. So sin is transgression of the
law.
Yeah. We'll leave it right there and
move on to our next one.
Moving on. Kenya Haynes says, "Elohim is
is the God family. What scripture can I
go to to show my daughter? I'm trying to
explain how there is only two, not
three."
All right. Elohim the God family and
trying to show that there's two in the
Godhead, not three. Guest caller.
Well, if you want to do that, then you
go and you read the Bible. See if you
can find three of them.
We doing read a few scripture, but this
is just a handful compared to
what's shown to show that ain't but two.
Let's first let's start in in Psalm 45.
And we're going to read 1 through 3.
Then we're going to skip.
Let me know when you finish three. Read
it.
Psalm 45.
Psalm 45:1-3.
My heart is inditing a good matter. I
speak of the things which I have made
touching the king. My tongue is the pen
of a ready writer.
Thou art fairer than the children of
men. Grace is poured into my thy lips.
Therefore God have blessed thee forever.
Gird thy sword upon thy thigh, O most
mighty, with thy glory and thy majesty.
Okay, skip down to
and read six and seven.
Thy throne, O God, is forever and ever.
The scepter of thy kingdom is a right
scepter. Thou lovest righteousness and
hatest wickedness. Therefore God, thy
God, have anointed thee with the oil of
gladness above thy fellows.
How many gods do you see there?
Two.
So let's go into Hebrews the first
chapter and find out who's who.
Hebrews chapter 1.
We'll read five and six.
And then you can skip down and read
eight
and nine.
For unto which of the angels said he at
any time, "Thou art my son, this day
have I begotten thee?" And again, "I
will be to him a father and he shall be
to me a son." And again, when he
bringeth in the first begotten into the
world, he saith, "And let all the angels
of God worship him."
Skip down.
>> to eight.
And nine.
But unto the Son he said, "Thy throne, O
God, is forever and ever. A scepter of
righteousness is a scepter of thy
kingdom. Thou has loved righteousness
and hated iniquity. Therefore God, even
thy God, have anointed thee with the oil
of gladness above thy fellows."
There are two, right?
Go into Psalms the second chapter.
Read 1 through 3.
1 through 3.
Why do the heathen rage
and the people imagine a vain thing? The
kings of the earth set themselves and
the rulers take counsel together against
the Lord and against his anointed,
saying, "Let us break their bands
asunder and cast away their cords from
us."
How many did you see there?
Two.
Think about it. Go into 10 chapter
Psalms verse 1.
Psalms 10 verse 1.
Why standest thou far off, O Lord? Why
hidest thyself
Psalm 110.
Oh, Psalms 110. My my bad.
>> [clears throat]
>> 110 and 1.
The Lord said unto my Lord, "Sit thou at
my right hand until I make thine enemies
thy footstool."
How many did you see?
Two.
Go to Isaiah 57 and read verse 15.
I just have two more places after this.
57? 57?
57 Isaiah 57 and 15.
For thus saith the high and lofty one
that inhabiteth eternity, whose name is
holy. I dwell in a high and holy place
with him
with him also
Mhm. Mhm. With him.
Oh, okay.
Finish it.
Also that is of a contrite and humble
spirit, to revive the spirit of the
humble and to revive the heart of the
contrite ones. I understand.
How many did you see?
Two. Two.
Now let's go into the
two last books in the Bible. Let's go
into Revelation 21st chapter.
We're going to read one and two.
And we're going to skip.
And I saw new heaven, a new heaven and a
new earth, for the first heaven and the
first earth were passed away and there
was no more sea. And I John saw the holy
city, New Jerusalem, coming down from
God out of heaven, prepared as a bride
adorned for her husband.
Now this is this is all of it now. This
is New Jerusalem. Ain't nobody else
left. So skip down and read verse 22 and
23.
And I saw no temple therein, for the
Lord God Almighty and the Lamb are the
temple of it.
And the city
How many was there?
It's two. Two.
Yeah.
And the city what? And the city had no
need of the sun, neither of the moon to
shine in it.
For the The of God did enlighten it and
the lamb is the light thereof.
How many is that?
That was two.
One last place, Revelation 22 and 1.
And he showed me a pure river of water
of life, clear as crystal, proceeding
out of the throne of God and of the
lamb.
Now, if you're going to have God the
Holy Ghost, the third one, don't you
think he should show up sooner or later?
Yeah.
He didn't show up
nowhere, even in the last two books of
the Bible, Revelation the last two
chapters of the last book.
There ain't no God the Holy Ghost, and
you can go all over the book. So, what
you want to do if you want to show your
daughter, read the book.
That's all I have to say.
All right.
So, can you show that to your daughter?
I know she going to go, "Wow."
Okay.
We're going to move on to our next.
Next one, Robert Dodge says,
"Blessed be the Lord. As a child, I was
taught in the Lord's Prayer the phrase,
'Forgive us our sins as we forgive those
who sin against us.' How did this come
about?"
All right, sound like the Lord's Prayer.
Julius, we had a lesson on that last
Sabbath. Shine some light.
How did it come about?
How did all this stuff come
come about? Let's go and look where it
came from.
Let's go to St. John.
St. John
the 12th chapter.
Uh brother Jerome, St. John chapter 12.
How did all the Jesus words come about?
And pick it up St. John
and pick it up at verse 47.
And let's look at how it how it's
written.
Go ahead, brother. St. John 12:47,
and we're going to skip to 49.
And if any man hear my words and believe
not,
I judge him not.
For I came not to judge the world, but
to save the world. Verse 49.
>> For I have not spoken of myself,
but the Father which sent me, he gave me
a commandment what I should say and what
I should speak. So, the word that Jesus
spoke was the Father's word. He gave
Jesus those words. Go ahead.
And I know that his commandment is life
everlasting.
Whosoever I or whatsoever I speak
thereof, even as the Father said unto
me, so I speak.
So, let's look at what he said.
St. John Matthew the 6th chapter.
Back up to Matthew chapter 6.
Jesus is the spokesman for the Father.
That's why you ain't never heard the
Father's voice or seen his shape at any
time. You've always dealt with the Son,
but he told you, "I can only speak what
my Father tell me." Matthew 6 and pick
it up at verse 11.
Uh uh uh uh pick it up at verse 11,
yeah.
Give us this day our daily bread.
And forgive us our debts as we forgive
our debtors. Skip down to verse 14.
For if you forgive men their trespasses,
your heavenly Father will also forgive
you.
He didn't say, "I will forgive you." He
said, "Your Father will forgive you." Go
ahead.
But if you forgive not men their
trespasses, neither will your Father
forgive your trespasses. That's how it
came about. Every word that Jesus spake
was what he was instructed by the
Father. That's why he said, "The words
are not mine, but my Father which sent
me. He told me what to say and what to
speak."
That's
how all this
came about. Jesus is the spokesman for
the Father.
He is called the word of God
cuz he was with the Father.
And they took sweet counsel together.
That's all I got.
All right.
Thank you for that. Hope that answered
your question as we move on to our next
one. Moving on, 12 Onyx asks, "Where can
we find the names of celestial things
written in the Bible?"
All right, celestial things.
Where can we find it at, brother Dre?
In Genesis 1. Let's go to Genesis 1.
Read verses 14 to 16.
Genesis 1:14 to 16.
Go ahead when you get it, brother.
And God said, "Let there be light in the
firmaments of the heavens to divide the
day from the night, and let them be for
signs and for seasons and for days and
years, and let them be for lights in the
firmament of the heaven to give light
upon the earth."
And it was so. And God made two great
lights, the greater light to rule the
day and the lesser light to rule the
night, and he made the stars also. So,
he's telling you what he made right here
in the heavens.
You know, uh let's go to Job 38. Job 38
and see
about some of the names of
constellations that he made.
Job 38 and pick it up at verse 31.
Job 38 and 31. Go ahead, brother.
Canst thou bind the sweet influences
of
Pleiades
or loose the bands of Orion? Mhm. Canst
thou bring forth Mazzaroth in his
season?
Or canst thou guide Arcturus with his
sons? Mhm.
Knowest thou the ordinances of heaven?
Canst thou set the dominion thereof in
the earth? So, hey, he just asked
questions about that, and he gave names,
but let's go to
Psalm 147 and read verse 4.
Psalm 147 and verse 4.
When you get there, go ahead, brother.
He telleth the number of the stars. He
calleth them all by their names. So, the
Lord called them all by their names.
But in terms of us calling them by their
names, you can read what Job is saying,
but then the purpose of those stars
being signs and all of that, you read
that in Genesis, the first chapter.
That's all I got.
Mhm.
All right.
>> Julius is saying something. You muted,
Julius.
First Jerome, read that read that Luke
21 and verse 25 only.
Show you God don't change.
Luke 21 and verse 25. And verse 25. Go
ahead. And there shall be signs in the
sun and in the moon and in the stars,
and upon the earth distress of nations
with perplexity, the sea and the waves
roaring. So, you got you the sun, stars,
and moon just like Genesis first chapter
like Dre said. And one more thing. This
is
Go to Amos 5 and read verse 8. That's
it.
Amos 5 and 8.
Read that when you get there, brother.
This is who we should seek, not the
stars, not the constellations
for for, you know, advice.
Amos 5 and 8. Go ahead, brother.
Seek him that maketh the seven stars
and Orion, and turneth the shadow of
death into the morning, and maketh the
day dark with night, that calleth for
the waters of the sea and poureth them
out upon the face of the earth. The Lord
is his name. That's who we should seek.
Okay, that's all I got.
You know, Dre, in that 1 Corinthians 15
and 40, it also talks about celestial
and terrestrial bodies as well. Yes,
sir, brother.
Yeah.
1 Corinthians 15 and 40.
Go ahead, brother, and Dre, take it from
there.
Pick [clears throat] it up at 39. Read
39 and 40.
1 Corinthians 15:39
and 40.
Yeah.
All flesh is not the same flesh, but
there is one kind of flesh of men,
another flesh
of beasts,
another of fishes, and another of birds.
There are also celestial bodies and
bodies terrestrial. But the glory of the
celestial is one, and the glory of the
terrestrial is another.
That's right.
That's right. And uh on your own, you
can read Deuteronomy 4 and verse 19.
The problem is a lot of people looked at
looked at the sun and the moon and the
stars and they were driven to worship
them and serve them but the Lord didn't
put those things up there for us to
worship them.
No. That's all I got.
Yeah. All right. Thank you for that,
brother.
Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next one.
Next one. Linda Stringer says, "Jesus
told the Jews in John 10 verse 26 that
they were not his sheep. Who are his
sheep? Are the Jews not descendants of
Israel?"
All right. First part about
asking about the sheep. Jesus told the
Jews in John. Let's go to that John 10
and 26.
That they were not his sheep. Yeah,
anybody that don't follow him and don't
want to obey him, how can you say that
you following the shepherd? Mhm. Let's
go to John 10 and pick it up at that 14,
brother. John 10 and pick it up at 14
and then we go Yeah, go ahead.
I am the good shepherd
and know my sheep and am known of mine.
Yeah, cuz his sheep are the ones that
follow him. Skip down to verse 19 and
20.
There was a division therefore again
amongst the Jews for these sayings.
And many of them said, "He have a devil
and is mad. Why hear ye him?" Now, if
you don't want to hear nothing the Lord
got to say and calling him the devil,
you can't be a sheep if you ain't going
to follow what he say. Skip down read 26
and 27.
But you believe not because you are not
of my sheep, as I said unto you, "My
sheep hear my voice and I know them and
they follow me."
Those are the ones that are his sheep.
The ones that hear his word and follow
his word and do what thus says the Lord.
Now, turn over to John 8. John 8th
chapter.
And we're going to pick it up at that
verse
29. John 8 and verse 29.
Go ahead.
And he that sent me is with me. The
Father have not left me alone, for I do
always those things that please him.
Yes. And so, when we want to do all
things that please the Lord, we have to
keep his word and obey it. Go ahead.
As he spake these words, many believed
on him.
Then said Jesus to those Jews which
believed on him, "If you continue in my
word, then are you my disciples indeed
and you shall know the truth and the
truth shall make you free." That's
right. And you his sheep when you hear
that word and continue in it, then you
are his disciples as well as his sheep,
but you don't want to have it, don't
want to hear it, you're not no sheep he
is. That's for sure.
So, um and the second part of that was
what, Deborah?
Uh the second part of it is, "Are Jews
Are the Jews not descendants of Israel?"
Yeah, Jews are descendants of Israel.
Actually, when you talk about Jew, we
talking about one of the tribes.
Israel makes up 12.
12 tribes make up Israel.
Yeah, from the
oldest to the youngest, we got Reuben,
Simeon, Levi, Judah, Dan, Naphtali, Gad,
Asher, Issachar, Zebulun, Joseph and
Benjamin.
And that's all I got. Anybody else?
All right. We'll go leave it there as we
keep rolling, Deborah. You know, our
time is a ticking.
Yes, moving on. Marquis Kimble asks, "In
Ecclesiastes 7 verse 26, is it really
talking about a woman and if so, what to
do if you are in a marriage with a woman
like this?"
Ecclesiastes 7 and verse 26. Let's go
there and read that and then the guest
caller will share some light on what are
you to do in this situation.
Read it.
And I found more bitter
than death the woman whose heart is
snares and nets and her hands as bands.
Whoso pleaseth God shall escape from
her, but the sinner shall be taken by
her.
Now, that's talking about a woman.
That's correct. Read Proverbs 22 and 14.
Proverbs 22 and 14.
The mouth of a strange woman is a deep
pit.
It
He that is
abhorred of the Lord shall fall therein.
So, that's that's messing around with
anybody other than your wife. That's a
strong That's a strange woman.
And you do that, the Lord ain't with
you.
But whatever this woman you got,
if she don't go out and lay with another
man, then
he is yours until you die or until the
Lord come.
Point blank.
That's all I got to say.
All right. Hope that answered your
question there as we move into our next
question.
Moving on. Read the Bible daily asks,
"Does the Bible
say how long Jesus will be in the
wilderness pleading with the people and
purging out the rebels before he returns
back to Jerusalem?"
So, we know in the book it says how
long.
But can you share some light, Jerome, on
how long will Jesus be in the
wilderness?
Well, the book let us know it's
uh a prophetic
week.
So, it's 3 and 1/2 years because there's
one week left in this prophecy in that
Daniel's uh 9th chapter, okay? So,
it's 3 and 1/2 years.
And that's that's a half a week. So,
let's go read it.
Daniel's uh 9 verse 27.
Jesus got to confirm the covenant for
one week. And in the midst of the week,
he got cut off. He got to finish that
other half.
Okay? And he going to do that in the
wilderness when he return, all right?
But let's read that uh Daniel's 9 verse
27.
And he shall confirm the covenant with
many for one week. And in the midst of
the week, he shall cause the sacrifice
and the oblation to cease. And for the
overspreading of abomination, he shall
make it desolate even until the
consummation and that determined shall
be poured upon the desolate.
So, when Jesus, he taught for 3 and 1/2
years,
that's that
half
of this week you read about in this 27
verse.
All right? Cuz one week is 7 years.
Okay? So, 3 and 1/2 years is a half of
that week. He taught for 3 and 1/2
years. Then they crucified and he died,
he rose on the third and ascended back
to heaven, sat down on right hand of the
Father, waiting to be making waiting,
okay? So, when he return, he going
fulfill that last half of week.
Okay? Or there's one week in this 27
verse and that's when he going teach
the people in the wilderness before
Israel is gathered to that wilderness.
All right? He going to gather them
there, he going to teach them there for
that last half a week, which is 3 and
1/2 years.
Okay?
Um
that's all I got on it.
All right.
Hope that answered your question there,
sister Deborah. Now, we're going into
new territory.
Uh yes, we are now into tonight's Q&A
for Wednesday, February the 4th, 2026.
Be Alert asks, "Is there examples of the
strangers backsliding besides Israel?
Why, if they backslide,
did not going into a captivity
since they too are considered to be
adopted?
So, are there examples of strangers
backsliding
besides Israel?"
All right. Let's
Let's open that up to the panel.
How can a stranger backslide from
something he never had? That is right.
Go to read Daniel's uh go read Romans 9
and and 1 through 4.
Yep. Yep.
I say the truth in Christ, I lie not. My
conscience also bear me witness in the
Holy Ghost
that I have great heaviness and
continual sorrow in my heart for I could
wish that myself were accursed from
Christ for my brethren, my kinsmen
according to the flesh, who are
Israelites, to whom pertaineth the
adoption and the glory and the covenants
and the giving of the law, and the
service of God, and the promises.
Do not what was given to the stranger?
Nothing.
>> Nothing.
Nothing. So, we don't know what it
actually is.
Yeah.
That's all I got to say.
And even in that Psalms 147, he showeth
his word unto Jacob, his statutes and
judgments unto Israel. He have not dealt
so with any nation.
And as for his judgments, they have not
known them. Praise ye the Lord. That's
right, cuz salvation is of Israel, of
the Jews. You want it, you got to go
through them.
That's right. Yes, sir. That is the
protocol. Yeah. All right. Hope that
answered your question there.
Next question, sis.
Next one, Nate Hudson asks, should all
males in your household be circumcised,
even your stepchildren?
If your wife never got it done because
she wasn't in the truth, is it up to the
head of uh
is it up to the head to enforce it or
leave it to God?
All right. Open to the panel about the
circumcision.
Should all males be done, even if you
might not be the biological father?
Uh-huh. Yes, caller, you got something
to weigh in on that.
That is the law.
That's right.
I don't care
uh uh
whether he's your child or
whatever. Let's go where is that?
Genesis 17 chapter. Let's go look and
see what the Lord said who's who.
Yeah.
Yes, sir.
17 and picking up
the Lord said, "This is my covenant."
Mhm.
Verse 10.
Yeah.
Read it.
This is my covenant, which ye shall keep
between [clears throat] me and you
and thy seed after thee.
Every man child among you shall be
circumcised. And ye shall circumcise the
flesh of your foreskin, and it shall be
a token of the covenant between me and
you.
And he that is eight days old shall be
circumcised among you. Every man child
in your generations. He that is born in
the house or bought with money of any
stranger, which is not of thy seed.
Keep reading.
He that is born in that house and he
that is bought with thy money must needs
be circumcised.
And my covenant shall be in your flesh
for everlasting covenant.
And the uncircumcised child whose flesh
of his foreskin is not circumcised, that
soul shall be cut off from his people.
He have broken my covenant.
Yeah.
So, now not only talking about Now, if
you're talking about a stranger that's
not even Israelite got to be circumcised
and he's the part of your household,
then your step-sons got to be
circumcised, too, and you are
responsible for, mister.
That's all I got to say.
Mhm. All right.
So, we're going to keep moving to our
next question.
All right, next question. And Evette has
uh several scriptures, but her question
is Evette says, "Are all references to
the sons of God in the Old Testament
relating only to angels? And are sons of
God in the New Testament
uh in reference to us? And then uh the
scriptures she gives are Genesis 6 verse
2,
Job 1 verse 6,
2 and 1,
Romans 8 verse 9,
and John 1
verse 12. I'll let you handle this,
Brother Cornell."
Okay.
Okay, so
the first one
is she wanted to know are the sons of
God referring to angels or men, right?
Right, in the Old Testament.
Okay.
>> Now, where you got
You got the angels, which is in Job.
Right. But then when you go to Genesis,
the sixth chapter, those are talking
about men.
Mhm. And the reason they called them
God is because as it said in 1
Corinthians, they are led by the spirit
of God.
And the daughters of men are the
daughters of Cain.
And if you keep reading in that sixth
chapter
of Genesis, you'll find out until Seth
was born and he started having children,
men did not call upon the name of the
Lord.
Yeah.
Because Seth
came out of Adam
and Cain was disinherited and Cain
and Abel was killed.
So, you got two sets of God sons of God
in the Old Testament, angels
and also the ones that's in the fifth
and sixth chapter of Genesis.
And all of the sons of God in the New
Testament,
what she said She said something about
Romans. What she say about Romans? Read
it.
>> Yeah, um
again, referenced Is it referenced to us
in the New Testament? And that's uh
Romans 8 verse 9 and John 1 verse 12.
Read them.
But ye are not in the flesh, but in the
spirit, if so be that the spirit of God
dwell in you.
Now, if any man have not the spirit of
Christ, he is none of his.
Uh-huh.
That's verse
That's verse uh 9.
But then
you should be Go ahead.
Okay.
And if Christ be in you,
then you are his.
Mhm.
Mhm. Go ahead.
It's also written
uh that all is led by the spirit of God
are the sons of God. Where is that
written at? Verse 14.
14. For as many as are led by the spirit
of God, they are the sons of God.
And see, that was the difference between
Adam and Seth's seed and Cain's seed.
Because they was led Cain's seed did not
call upon the Lord
and and Adam and Seth's seed was led by
the word of God.
And that's why they was
their sons. That's why when it said when
the sons of God looked upon the
daughters of men
and took as many to wife, the Lord said,
"My spirit shall not always strive with
man." In other words,
them evil daughters of Cain
is going to change the mind of
the righteous son of Adam
and Seth.
Mhm.
Now, you got one physical set of sons,
which are the angels. Job talks about
them.
And they're also called the sons of the
morning.
It's in Job.
But the sons of God that hooked up with
women
are flesh and blood men.
Angels do not
procreate.
They are spirit, just like God. And the
only reason God is going to be able to
have some children, he have to adopt.
That's when you your body is changed.
That is the physical when you become the
physical son of God. Now, let's go into
Romans, the first chapter, and start
reading at verse 1.
Paul, a servant of Jesus Christ, called
to be an apostle, separated unto the
gospel of God,
which he had promised afore by his
prophets in the holy scriptures,
concern concerning his son, Jesus
Christ, our Lord, which was made of the
seed of David according to the flesh,
and declared to be the son of God with
power according to the spirit of
holiness by the resurrection from the
dead.
So, now that's when we will become
the son of God with power when our body
is raised
incorruptible and immortal. Or either we
are changed if we should live till the
Lord come.
But other than that,
you got three sets of sons of God. You
got the angels,
then you got the people that walks in
the word of God as long as they were led
by their son, and then the people that's
going to be raised in the resurrection.
Those are the sons of God with power.
That's all I have to say. Mhm.
And they they had a question about that
John 1 and 12, and that just backed up
what you said about
uh read that 1 and 12. It's the same as
we just read in that Romans uh
brother. For as many as are led by the
spirit of God, they are the sons of God.
Read that John 1 and 12. Same thing. But
as many as received him, to them gave he
power to become the sons of God, even to
them that believe on his name.
That's it. Yep.
Long as you believe on his name
you going to walk in his ways. You are
the spiritual son of God, but then that
gave you the power to become the
physical son of God.
That's right.
Amen. Amen. Everybody Everybody on this
panel is looking forward to that change
of doing just that.
All right. We hope that that answered
your question as we continue to move on
to our next one.
Uh the time is 9:00. Oh, see, when you
having fun, that time really does fly.
All right. We uh want to say that we
have come to the end of our show. We
thank you all from all around the world
who sent in those questions. And we say
that if you submitted a question we
didn't get to it, please don't resubmit
it. Sister Deborah take it and she will
put it in rotation and we will address
that question next week. So, until we
all come together again, we say please
be safe, be blessed, stay prayed up, and
may the Lord have mercy on us all as
Brother Jerome closes us out.
Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread and
forgive us of our debts as we forgive
our debtors. And lead us
not into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom and the
power and the glory forever. In Jesus'
name we